All right, traders. You're watching the
most woke Forex channel on here, hosted
by, you know, Hunter, the the most
attractive, handsome, jacked Forex
trader in the world, not to not to be so
humble. All right, so today, guys, if
you're new here, make sure you hit the
subscribe, obviously. We're going to be
looking at a strategy that I wanted to
make for some beginners. Going into
2021, I'm sure there's going to be a ton
of people coming onto the Forex scene
saying, "Hey, what's this Forex thing?"
Maybe Bitcoin has got you a little bit
intrigued in Forex or something like
this, and you want to make a little bit
of money. Now, the way I trade
does not use indicators. So, you guys
might be questioning, "Hey, Hunter, why
the hell are you making a RSI trading
strategy method, right? Why are you
giving this away?" It's something that's
going to be very very simple. It's
something that's going to be related to
how I trade, but it's going to be much
easier for you guys to understand if you
are a beginner trader. If you do want to
use the RSI, because as a price action
trader, I do not need RSI. I can see
divergences. I can see how the price
flows simply by looking at the
candlesticks. With the RSI, it's going
to be a lot easier for you guys. It's
going to be very very simple for a
beginner to understand. We're going to
jump into it right now. We're going to
look at how you can make money using a
dumbed-down version of what I use, and
then from there, you can expand to
become the most secondary woke trader in
the Forex community.
So, like usual, guys, if you are new
here, hit that subscribe button. And if
you're old here, hit that like button.
You only have to hit one button each
time. You guys know this stuff's going
to be good. So, let's jump into this
strategy. It's going to be a divergence
strategy, first of all. So, we're going
to be looking at what's essentially
slowing momentum, slowing power of the
markets. And this is going to indicate a
reversal happening very soon. And then
we're going to look for the actual
reversal happening, and then we're going
to look for the entry. All right, guys.
Being that I am the most woke teacher,
most woke Forex trader, we're going to
break this down in incredibly freaking
simple terms. Um
just such a way that you guys can
understand it. I'm
going to teach this to you so, so
simply. What we can be doing, first of
all, bunch of stuttering there. Oh my
god. Okay. Uh what we can be doing is
either trend trading or counter-trend
trading. It's going to be a lot easier
to be spotting the counter-trend trades.
So, with the RSI divergence, what we're
essentially going to be looking for is a
if there's a trend going up like this,
that the divergence is going to become
present when it slows down in the market
here, breaking this down very quickly,
and then you're going to look for that
reversal, and then you're going to look
for the retest and the entry, and then
you're going to be looking to go down.
Now, with the trend trading, it's
essentially you're going to be looking
at the higher time frame, and then it's
going to be a lower time frame, and then
you're going to be trying to
gather back into that market using that
RSI divergence. Hopefully, that makes a
lot of sense. So, what you ideally want
to be looking for if you are wanting to
have a higher probability, is you're
going to be looking for this higher time
frame
pullback, and then the RSI change back
into the trend here, right? If you guys
are doing this the other way around, you
have this is generally what you guys are
going to be wanting to do is look for
these like reversals here,
and that's not necessarily going to be
the best way to do it, but you can get
bigger swings this way. So, that's how
I'm breaking it down right off the bat.
Um if you guys want to be more accurate,
you're going to have to look more like
this style, following that uptrend.
Okay, now guys, breaking it down once
again, uh make it very simple for you
guys. There's going to be essentially
three phases of how we're going to be
trading. First phase, we're going to be
spotting the RSI. So, first of all,
let's look at the divergence, the actual
RSI divergence, very very simple here.
Look for only the regular ones. So
simple for beginners. What we're going
to be looking for is essentially the
price to be continuing to make lower
lows or higher highs if it's going in
the other direction. And then the
indicator showing the exact opposite.
So, what this is indicating is saying,
"Okay, the strength of the market is
weakening for how the price is actually
acting." So, we're actually looking at
each consecutive lower low is getting
weaker essentially. That That's what
that means. The momentum is dissipating.
We're no longer able to push to new lows
very powerfully. So, this move is very
weak. And this is getting higher up. So,
it's most likely that the price is going
to follow that indicator in the opposite
way. It's true for the bearish side
here. You guys can figure it out. You
can pause the video and look at it. I
don't need to explain it in great
detail.
The next setup here, the next thing that
we're going to be looking for. So, let's
say we have a price is going up and the
RSI So, here's the RSI down here. You
can ignore my writing.
Um RSI and the RSI is down here and it
is going up also, but then it starts
breaking down, right? And now it's down
here, right? So, what we're going to be
doing is basically lining up. So, you
know,
uh let's say that this actually lined up
here properly. Um so, this is actually
going up and this is going down, right?
So, that's essentially what you're
looking for. So, this is going to be the
case where we say, "Okay,
and this is price, right? Boop, price.
Um
this is where we're going to say, "Okay,
we want to enter, but we don't want to
enter right away." Uh so, we're going to
look for some sort of entry requirement.
So, what we're going to look for is on
the price, we want to look for this
pullback. The RSI is obviously going to
pull back for a third time here, kind of
hit that line. You know, we don't go
based off of that though. I'm going to
make this a little bit more advanced and
you guys are going to get really
accurate entries. So, what we're going
to do is we're going to look for the
pullback here
and then we're going to look for some
sort of level that we can short on there
and then short it back down, right? And
then we're going to be able to take this
move and then we're going to be able to
target something.
Now, the third phase is actually running
with the trade. So, after you've taken
this entry,
how are we going to run with that trade?
So, let's just dive into this really
quickly.
All right, guys. So, I quickly pulled up
EUR/USD and um I particularly use price
action, so I was able to spot this
pretty quickly um kind of this reversal
here. But, this is exactly what we're
going to be looking for. And what I
would like you to do, you know, always
use at least two time frames something
like this so you can pinpoint some
entries. So, what I've seen here is I
see
um I see price going higher here, right?
And I see obviously the RSI getting
lower here. Now, if it's parallel,
that's perfectly fine, too. The whole
point is to show that the RSI is
weakening in respect to the price.
Generally, you're going to notice it
pretty much matches the price. But, this
is where we want to find the divergence
in the price, right? So, once you see
that divergence confirm here and you can
see, you know, it's after it's broken
down here, right? So, you're not going
to be able to catch this very peak.
That's what maybe other traders are
going to tell you you're going to be
able to catch this peak. It's not
possible because you're not going to see
that the divergence is actually
happening
until it breaks back down here, right?
So, when it breaks back down here,
you're looking uh roughly around here as
your area that you're going to notice
the price actually diverging, right? And
you're not going to want to just enter
right away. You're going to want to wait
for this retest, right? So, let's just
jump in. So, now we've noticed the RSI
divergent happen on a higher time frame.
What we want to do is we want to jump
down here. Let's put a purple box there
so I can just find it on a lower time
frame. I like to use 5 minute as entry.
My Mind you, I don't use RSI divergence.
This is just a beginner strategy, right?
So, what we've clearly seen is we've
really shown weakness in the market
here. And now what we want to do is we
want to look for
um an entry, right? So, what we look for
is I'm going to break this down pretty
simple is we want to look for areas that
could be untested. So, big drop-off
areas that there's probably still a lot
of resting orders. Now, I'm putting that
rather simply for you guys um because
I'm assuming that you guys are rather
rather tively uh beginners. If you guys
want to learn more, please jump into the
streams and whatnot. I'm just doing this
in a very quick video um so you guys can
kind of see. So, you can just kind of
see that this was a massive dump-off
right here. You kind of have one around
here as well. I'm not going to give you
exact entries, but this looks pretty
good, right? There was some
consolidation here and then it was a
massive dump-off right there. So, you
can actually see that I've pinpointed
the entry quite well.
So, what I would do is I would wait
until it comes up to this area and then
I would wait to see that it's actually
confirming that it's breaking back down,
right? So, we're showing that this
candle is actually closing back down,
right? So, we're seeing the weakness in
the market once again right at that
level that we want to see. And then what
we're going to do is we're going to
place our stop just above there, which
is the previous point of the RSI and
then we're going to be targeting what we
can do is target this first low here
that I actually created, right? We can
target that low because that was a
previous point where it was able to
bounce off of again. So, most likely
it's going to bounce off of that area
relatively quickly again. You can also
take profits along the way at other
points where it bounced off of, right?
So, another option would be right around
here, right?
And you could shoot right around here as
well. So, you could break that down into
three three take profits.
Now, this is basically coming down to
our third criteria, running with the
trade. So, what I'm going to say is take
majority of your profit right around
that low that was created before it came
back to retest your zone. And you're
going to want to shoot for two to three
R each time with that take profit, and
then you can take profit along the way,
and you can leave some of a runner if
you want. That's going to be up to you.
That's the third phase. That's going to
be the phase that you're going to have
to play around with the most and see
what works for you in your strategy, but
really let things run as long as you
can. And this is actually going to be a
good trade because you know you would
hit that take profit. You maybe wouldn't
have hit this one. You would have hit
this one, right? So, let's just look for
maybe another one if we kind of scroll
through. So, I actually found it super
super quick. It's basically the exact
same spot. I just deleted those other
ones. But, what we're going to notice
here this time is I'm going to show you
how to do the trend trading type version
of this. And if we just want to jump,
and we can put this back to a clean
chart up top.
Get rid of volume cuz I don't care about
volume. Perfect. Okay, so we see
obviously an uptrend on this higher time
frame. So, we want to be following that
uptrend. That first example I showed you
guys, that was the very easy way to find
these RSI divergences, and that's what
naturally you're going to be looking
for. Mind you, you're going to have
better luck if you're following the
trend. And this is where people are
generally going to go wrong kind of with
this strategy.
You can do both. They both work. It's
just you're going to be a higher hit
rate, but you're probably going to shoot
for a lower profit
with trading with the trend because
you're not going to be able to gather as
big swings. Right. So, what we see here
is we see a
higher time frame again going into the
upside. We see a reversal back to the
downside. Now, we see What do we see
here? An RSI divergence with low lower
lows here.
And then down here, we see it coming
back up, right?
Coming back up.
Right there. Right? So, mind you, you
know, your first instinct might be
to see that you're seeing an RSI
divergence right here with it coming
back up, and you might put your stop
right there, and then you might get
stopped out, and then it rallies. This
is the case of the game. Sometimes you
might want to put your stop a little bit
wider. This is obviously something that
you guys got to play with. I'm not here
to cater for you, right? I'm giving you
a strategy that can help you start
trading and give you a good idea of how
the market works. I am not here to make
you profitable. That I'm just That's
what I'm saying right now. Nobody is
going to carry your hand and make you
profitable on YouTube. You're going to
have to do the work yourself. But, you
can see multiple times it's diverging,
right? And then eventually it breaks to
the upside. So, maybe you would have
entered right around here a second time
or something like that, and then you
would have maybe been able to get this.
I'm showing you this in the case that
this is essentially what could go wrong
because you never know exactly when it's
diverging, and this is kind of the
problem with the RSI divergence
in that
my trading strategy, I would not be
entering here because I have different
criteria. But, the RSI divergence, this
is where it fails because it could
diverge, and then it could still break
to lower lows. It's more likely It's
less likely on how I trade with price
action-based trading. Again, guys, if
you guys want to learn more about this,
uh please jump into uh the streams and
whatnot, and you can start learning. So,
here we're going to see that lower time
frame, we're going to see that reversal
to the upside, and then you're going to
look for an entry. Now, mind you, you
might not have gotten an entry here
because it might not have pulled back to
that area that we would have wanted to,
right? We would have wanted to enter on
kind of an area where it blasted off of.
You would have wanted to enter here with
a with a stop below there. But, that's
perfectly fine. I'm literally just
showing you the two very first things
that I saw on the chart, um because I am
not one to cherry pick and show you that
this is absolute perfect strategy.
No strategy is, and no strategy is ever
going to be getting you a 80% hit rate.
Unless you're just
20 years down the line into trading. You
guys would be happy if you can get a 50%
win rate. That's what I would say. If
you're shooting for 2R, 3R, things like
this. All right, guys. Like I said,
that's all I want to talk about with
that strategy. It's
only goal here is to get you thinking
about how to be trading, why markets are
moving different ways. This is all just
a starter thing that you can start
trading with. It is something that you
will have to adjust to make your own
style, but RSI divergences can be a
profitable strategy. Not super
profitable. I'll tell you this right
now. RSI divergences are not as good as
price action trading, but they're very
easy for beginners to understand because
you can kind of see that that diagonal
line. So, I perfectly understand why you
guys want to do it, and everybody asks
me on the stream all the time, "RSI
divergence, so you know, what's it's
what's it all about? Why is it so good?"
It's not good. It's It's slightly
profitable if you're good at it, right?
Uh price action is king, and you should
start with RSI because that's the only
indicator I would actually suggest as a
beginner. Everything else is garbage.
So, if you guys like what you see here,
please hit make sure you hit the
subscribe button and follow the streams
along. There is a Discord in the
description that you can join, as well
as my Instagram. I post there pretty
much um sometimes. You guys know. I will
see you guys next time, and uh happy New
Year. I hope your trading dreams come
true.
Goodbye.
Listen.
Or or I